# [Ryan Wang]

[ryanwang@cmail.carleton.ca] | [613-4156006] | [ON, CA] | [trainkin.com] system engineer, software developer, web application developer

## **Summary**

An innovative thinker, initiative taker professional with software engineering. Offering more than 4 yrs of experience in the full software development lifecycle - from concept through delivery of applications and solutions. Experience in design, analysis, implementation, and test. Willing to take ownership of core components.

### **Education**

- [Carleton University], [Ottawa], [Canada]
- Bachelor, Computer science, 2015 2017
  - o [University of Ottawa], [Ottawa], [Canada]
  - o BCS Courses Exchange, 2016 spring fall
- [Hunan University of Arts and Science], [Hunan], [China]
- Bachelor's Degree, Telecommunications Engineering, 2007 2011

### **Skills & Endorsements**

Software Development, Server Architecture, Web Applications, Search Engine Technology, Web Crawling, Agile methodology, Performance and scalability optimization, API design, Data warehousing and analytics.

- Programming Languages: Python, C, Java, C++, JavaScript, HTML5, Go, Ruby on Rails, SQL, NoSQL, Racket, Prolog, Clojure, C#, AngularJS
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Memcached, HBase,
- Platform & Tools: Tornado, Hadoop, Elasticsearch, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Nginx, Qt, Android Studio, Visual Studio, Git, Vim, IntelliJ IDEA, OpenCV, Eclipse, LaTex, Tensor Flow, Django.

# **Experience**

[Dates 2017.9 – current]

### [Software Developer] | [T24 defence] | [Ottawa]

Member of development team. Participated in message handler, including information exchange, through sensors (track24, whisper, T24 pocket) and satellite (iridium). Built automated front end testing, implemented simulator, built REST APIs, and collected feedback and fix issues.

### [Dates 2015.7 – 2015.9] [3 months]

# [Server Development Engineer (Back end Developer)] | [Shou (mobile app company)] | [Beijing]

Member of backend development team. Enhanced and improved company product - ShouTV, archived

online payment process (google play, apple pay), programming logic optimization, REST APIs for client-side (IOS, android).

#### [Dates 2013.10 - 2015.3] [1 year 6 months]

# [Server Development Engineer (Back end Developer)] | [Adesk (mobile app company)] | [Beijing]

Member of backend server department team. Responsible for building and maintaining backend services for company product - android wallpaper,

Built REST API (With python + tornado + MongoDB + Redis + Memcached) to response client-side's request (IOS, android), developed efficient search functions (using elasticsearch).

Also, as a member of data analysis team, we used Hadoop to store big data and built analysis programs for company 'department of commercial market'. Managed cluster storage (using MongoDB) and monitored servers status (Nagios).

Standalone project: A web application - Android-ringing: android ringing application (providing mobile ringing service to android users). As the leader of the project, my role was to lead client side team and build the server side of the project - backend (with python + tornado) and frontend (html5 + bootstrap CSS + js), interface design and massive data exchange with client side.

#### [Dates 2012.1 – 2013.6] [1 year 6 months]

### [Software Engineer] | [TRS - (Search engine dev company)] | [Beijing]

Member of development No.3 department, Developed and maintained search engine, web spider, proxy servers (company products) with colleagues.

Responsible for distributed heavy tasks, built tools for authenticated user, batch task generating program, multi-threaded web server and many associated tools.

In panda project (chinese government project): government private web spider and search engine. my role was to develop tools to support and maintain company spiders.

#### [Dates 2011.5 - 2012.1] [9 months]

## [Technical Service Engineer (Server side technology assistant)] | [<u>Tsinghua</u> <u>Tongfang</u>] | [Beijing]

Member of computer production team. Troubleshoot for PC users: handled software installation and configuration, built script for cluster servers;

Windows System Configuration: built Exchange 2010, Lync, SCCM, CRM;

Linux System Configuration: built KVM, XEN, LAMP, postfix, BIND, DHCP, etc.

## Languages

Chinese - Native, English - Professional (working proficiency)

## Certifications

MCITP Microsoft, License D238-2597 Starting April 2011

# **Interests**

Web application | Machine Learning | Computer Vision | Mobile application | Real Time OS | Data analysis | Algorithm | Math | Reading | Videogames | Computational Linguistics